>> 凯尔: 在这些基本类型中，我们应该有特殊的值
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Within those primitive types
there are special values that we should
请注意。
pay attention to.
有几个但
And there are a number of them but
我想把注意力集中在两个特定的特殊价值观上。
I wanna focus our attention on
two specific special values.
这些作物比我们想要的要多的多，或者至少
These are ones that crop up much more
often than we would like, or at least some
其中至少有一个比我们想的要多
of them, at least one of them crops
up more often than we would like.
他们的意识能让我们避免虫子
And awareness of both of them
is gonna help us avoid bugs and
在某些情况下，甚至可以从我们的 JavaScript 语言中获得更多的能量。
in some cases, even get more power
out of our JavaScript language.
让我们看看第一个被称为 NaN的
So let's look at the first
one it's referred to as NaN,
这个词的首字母缩写不是数字
which is supposedly an acronym for
not a number.
从历史上看 NaN 至少是用 JavaScript来的
Historically, that's where it comes from,
NaN comes to us at least in JavaScript,
它是通过 IEEE 754 规范来的，数字规范。
it comes by way of the IEEE 754 spec,
the number spec.
本质上 NaN 并不表示不是数字
Essentially NaN doesn't mean not
a number essentially it means
这种特殊的值指示了指示无效数字的 sentinel 值。
this special what we call sentinel
value that indicates an invalid number.
这比你说的不是个数字好得多
That's a much better mental model for
it than referring to it is not a number,
我们应该把它当作一个无效的数字，让我们深入研究这个问题。
we oughta refer to at as an invalid
number, so let's dig into that.
我们怎么就像个南人呢 ?
How do we arrive at something like a Nan?
第一，你可以把那些数字表示的东西
Well, number one, you can take things
that are representations of numbers in
字符串形式，在这种情况下。
string form, in this case.
举个例子，我现在的年龄是 38 岁，我也可以
Like for example, my age at the moment
is 38, and I can represent that either
引用第 38 条或第 1 行的第 1 行，我可以用八进制表示。
as quote 38 or, in this case, on line 1,
I could represent it in octal.
八进制表示为 46。
The octal representation being 46.
我不喜欢那个
I don't like that one,
因为它让我听起来很老所以不想用这个
cuz that makes me sound a lot older so
I don't wanna use that.
但我可以用字符串形式表示，然后我有一个数字，就像 38号。
But I can represent it in string form, and
then I have a number, like the number 38.
或者我可以引用 " 39 " 来引用我的下一个年龄。
Or I can do quote 39 to
reference my next age.
我不再拥有猫了所以当我说我的猫的年龄
I don't own cats anymore, so
when I say my cat's age, and
我使用不适用的内容，没有数字可用来引用该内容。
I use something like not applicable
there's no number to use to refer to that.
让我非常明确地告诉你 0 号是
And let me be very specific and
clear with you the number 0 is
不是您指示缺少有效数字值的方式。
not the way you indicate
the absence of valid numeric value.
与数学数学家交谈，数字 0 绝对是一个重要的数字。
Talk to any math mathematician, the number
0 is absolutely an important number.
它是一个对它有实质内容的数字。
It is a number that has substance to it.
在任何形式上都不合适
It's not appropriate in any way shape or
以 0 作为缺少数字值的占位符的形式。
form to think of 0 as being the place
holder for absence of numeric value.
这在数学上是没有意义的，而且在编程上也没有意义。
Doesn't make sense mathematically and
doesn't make sense programatically.
那么我们应该用多少呢 ?
So what number should we use?
这就是为什么 IEEE 在定义特殊的比特模式时做的
Well, that's why IEEE did when they
defined the special bit pattern that
表示这是我们指出的数字。
represents this is
the number that we indicate.
这不是有效数字，我不能用 n/a做任何事情。
It's not a valid number,
I can't do anything with n/a.
基本没有数字系统，其中 n/a
There's essentially no
number system where n/a
是数字 [LAUGH] 的有效表示，除非您发明了一个数字。
is a valid representation of a number
[LAUGH] unless you invented one.
因此我们得到 NN 的支持，我们会得到无效的号码。
So we get NaN back,
we get the invalid number back.
顺便说下当你做的数字无效时
And by the way,
when you do things with an invalid number,
即使是那些看似疯狂的事情
even things that seem crazy,
like subtracting strings,
你会得到无效的号码
you're gonna get invalid number back.
第 4 行，我的年龄减，然后是字符串，就像我儿子的年龄一样，
Line 4, my age minus, and
then a string, like my son's age,
不管怎么说都没有什么意义
doesn't actually make any sense,
not programatically, anyway.
但 JavaScript 有一种思考方式，我们常常掩饰。
But JavaScript has a way of thinking
about this that we often gloss over.
特别地， JavaScript 认为这是负运算符需要数字，
In particular, JavaScript thinks about
this as the minus operator needs numbers,
它只为数字定义的
it's only defined for numbers.
当你给它不是数字的时候
When you give it something
that is not a number,
>> 凯尔: 然后它说，
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Then it says,
我得把它变成数字
I need to turn it into a number.
这就是我们在一点点的压力下谈论的话题。
That's what we'll talk about when we
get into coercion in a little bit.
所以说我儿子的年纪
So, it turns the, quote, my son's age,
他 8岁的时候我儿子的年龄
which by the way he's 8, my son's age,
把他的年龄变成了 NaN 值
it turns his age,
that string into the NaN value.
所以当我说我的年龄减时，我实际上是在说我的年龄减去 NaN ，
So when I say my age minus,
I'm actually saying my age minus NaN, and
NaN 与任何其他数学运算始终是 NaN， cuz 是无效的。
NaN with any other mathematical operation
is always NaN, cuz it's invalid.
所以 NaN 将所有方法传播出去。
So NaN sort of propagates all the way out.
没有你能做的包括 NaN 和
There's nothing that you can
ever do that includes a NaN and
结果除了 NaN 之外的任何东西都是数学上的
results in anything other than a NaN,
mathematically anyway.
顺便说一下你会发现即使我的猫年龄是 NaN
And by the way, you'll notice that
even though my cat's age is NaN,
它不等于它本身，或者至少是按三等号运算符，
it is not equal to itself, or at least
according to the triple equals operator,
它不等于自己
it's not equal to itself.
很多人喜欢相信三重等号运算符告诉你
Many people like to believe that
the triple equals operator tells you
但我要告诉你三大代表的谎言
the truth, but I have news for
you the triple equals operator lies.
它告诉你这两个东西并不是平等的。
It tells you that those
two things are not equal.
之所以这样做并不是因为布兰登 - 艾希当天发疯了。
And the reason it does that is not
because Brendan Eich was crazy that day.
因为 IEEE 说 NN 不相等。
It does that because IEEE said
NaNs are not equal to each other.
实际上， NaN 是唯一存在的价值，至少在 JavaScript中，
As a matter of fact, NaN is the only value
in existence, at least in JavaScript,
这是唯一没有我们所说的身份财产的价值
it's the only value that does not have
what we call the identity property,
意思就是不等于自己。
meaning it is not equal to itself.
只有这才是真正的价值
It's the only value where that is true.
>> 扬声器 2: 未定义，未定义相同 ?
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Undefined,
undefined's the same?
>> 凯尔: 未定义完全等于自身。
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Undefined is
absolutely equal to itself.
NaN 是唯一不等于自身的值。
NaN is the only value that
is not equal to itself.
所以我们需要某种方式来确定因为三重等于我们
So we need some way to determine
because triple equals lies to us,
我们需要一些方法来确定这个值是否实际上是 NaN。
we need some way to determine
if the value is in fact NaN.
而 JavaScript 最初是用一个叫做 isNaN的实用程序提供的，
And JavaScript shipped originally
with a utility called isNaN,
当我们把一个像个号码的东西递给它时我们就正确地得到了假
which when we pass a thing like
a number to it we correctly get false.
当我们通过一个事实时，合法的是 NaN ，我们会得到真实的。
And when we pass a thing that actually,
legitimately is NaN, we get true.
看起来很棒直到我们看到第 10 行
Seems great until we look at line
10 when we pass in something that
肯定不是数字，是我儿子的年龄。
is definitely not a number,
the string my son's age.
但是，让我问你这个问题，这不是一个数字，我们同意，但是
But let me ask you the question,
it's not a number, we agree with that, but
是 NaN 值吗 ?
is it the NaN value?
当然不是。
Most definitely not.
那么为什么我们还能得到真正的真相呢 ?
So why do we still get true?
历史的真正原因，是由于某种原因，
The historical reason for getting true,
is because for some reason, the isNaN
实用程序将值强制为数字，然后将其检查为 NaN。
utility coerces values to numbers
before it checks for them to be NaN.
>> 凯尔: 所以，它会强迫把我儿子的年龄串到一个数字上，
&gt;&gt; Kyle: So, it's gonna coerce
the string my son's age to a number and
你猜它会强迫它吗
guess what number it's gonna coerce it to?
NaN 值，所以它当然会恢复为 true。
The NaN value, so
of course it's gonna back true.
你猜我是怎么知道的
Now, guess how I know that it does that.
我看了这个规格，而且这个规格很清楚的说，强迫它一个号码。
I read the spec, and the spec very
clearly says, coerce it to a number.
这一错误发生在最初的 JavaScript中
Sometime after that mistake
happened in initial JavaScript,
他们觉得这是个坏主意
they decided that's a bad idea.
因此，在 ES6 中，我们有更好的实用程序 Number.isNan 实用程序。
So with ES6, we got a better utility,
the Number.isNan utility.
而这个 Number.isNan 让我们坚定地告诉我们它是 NaN 值，也不是。
And that Number.isNan tells us defiantly
for sure it's the NaN value or it's not.
换句话说，它对我们没有任何胁迫。
In other words it doesn't
do any coercion for us.
它告诉我们确切的数字。
It tells us specifically it's the number.
就像回到你的问题一样， NaN是什么 ?
So like going back to your
question about what is NaN?
如果我做数字运算
Well, if I do a numeric operation and
我要返回我期待的类型的值
I get back a value what
type am I expecting back
从每一个数字运算中
from every single numeric operation?
我在等一个号码对吧
I'm expecting a number, right?
记住我说 NN 是 IEEE 754 规范的一部分
And remember I said NaNs are part
of the IEEE 754 spec which is
数字表示规范。
a numeric representation specification.
令人费解的是， NaN 的类型是数字。
So perplexingly,
the type of a NaN is number.
只是一个无效的号码
It's just an invalid number.
这就是为什么认为这不是数字是不恰当的原因
Which is why it's not appropriate to think
of it as not a number because then you
就会很奇怪不是号码的那种字眼是号码吗
get into that weirdness the wording
of type of not a number is number?
那是因为把它想象成一个数字是错误的
That's because it's wrong to
think of it as not a number,
最好把它想象成无效的数字
it's better to think of
it as an invalid number.
当然，号码类型和无效号码肯定是号码。
And of course the type of and
invalid number is definitely number.
我有很多人向我建议他们不应该不做 NN nevermind 的事
I have people suggest to me no no no they
should have never done NaN nevermind what
EEE 754 说。
I EEE 754 said.
他们不应该做 NaN ，我们应该把其他东西还给他们。
They never should have done NaN,
we should have returned something else.
真的吗
Really?
我们从一个数字运算中返回的
What should we return from
a numeric operation that's
不是号码的人吗
gonna be not of the type number?
我们可以重新定义，但这不是数字。
We could return back undefined,
but that's not numeric.
这是一个糟糕的想法，给开发者一个诱饵和开关。
That's a terrible idea, to give developers
something that's a bait and switch.
我们可以再回去了糟糕的想法
We could maybe return back null,
terrible idea.
我们可以返回错误，可怕的想法，我们可以返回，唉， -1。
We could return back false, terrible idea,
we could return back, ugh, -1.
这是旧的，历史的，当你做什么索引的时候，
This is old, historical,
when you do something like index of, and
无法在您的字符串或数组中找到任何内容。
it can't find something in your string or
array.
因为在过去的 C 天里，你只能返回号码，他们不是 IEEE 754。
Because in the old C days, you could only
return numbers, and they weren't IEEE 754.
所以他们唯一能出来的号码是什么
So what was the only
number they could come up
表示找不到或无效的搜索吗 ?
with to represent didn't find it or
invalid search?
他们选择了 -1，就像 40 年前一样。
They chose -1, which was fine for
them like 40 years ago.
我不知道为什么我们用 JavaScript 来做，但我们做了。
I don't know why we adopt it
in a JavaScript but we did.
因此，当更合适的时候，我们的一些 API 将返回 -1 。
So we have some of our APIs that return
back -1, when the more appropriate
我们用语言表达的数字，代表我没有发现它是 NaN。
number that we had in the language,
to represent I didn't find it as NaN.
如果你在设计一个系统你想回去
If you're designing a system,
and you wanna return and
有人希望得到一个号码你想向他们发出信号
somebody expects to get a number and
you wanna signal to them there's no valid
我要给你的号码只有一个意义上的意义
number for me to give there is only
one value that makes any sense at all.
你应该把 NaN 送回去
You should return the NaN.
但我在这份名单上的任何其他投诉都是
But more than any other complaint
that I have on this list is when
人们尝试引用 0 作为 NaN 的占位符。
people try to refer to 0 as
somehow a placeholder for NaN.
我们会回到这个和胁迫的时刻。
And we'll come back to this and
coercion and just a moment.
所以 NaN ，它是一个数字，它是无效的数字，
So NaN, it is a number, and
it is the invalid number, and
它会发生在你的节目里，不可能，它会，
it is going to occur in your programs,
not maybe, it will, and
你应该对它进行适当的测试
you should be testing for
it appropriately.
否则，您会有错误，而您无法处理这些错误。
Otherwise, you have bugs and
you're not handling those bugs.